<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows Autopilot on MEM v ENNBEE - Battles with Modern Device Management</title>
    <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/tags/autopilot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows Autopilot on MEM v ENNBEE - Battles with Modern Device Management</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© 2024 Nick Benton, MEM v ENNBEE</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 21:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memv.ennbee.uk/tags/autopilot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Windows Store Apps Updated with Microsoft Intune</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/updating-windows-store-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 21:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/updating-windows-store-apps/</guid>
      <description>So we&amp;rsquo;re all onboard with the New Microsoft Store, and deploying both UWP and Win32 apps from Microsoft Intune is an absolute breeze, and reduces the effort of deploying applications to a click click next OK exercise. What about the UWP apps that are already installed on a Windows Autopilot device, shouldn&amp;rsquo;t we give them a bit of love?</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/updating-windows-store-apps/feature-storeapps.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-Managing Windows Autopilot Hybrid Join Devices</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/configmgr-client-hybrid-autopilot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 21:26:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/configmgr-client-hybrid-autopilot/</guid>
      <description>As both Microsoft Intune and Configuration Manager are a match made in heaven, there are many reasons to still utilise both, either using Co-Management or just plain old Tenant Attach, so imagine my joy when Microsoft released Co-Management Authority in Intune, and I thought the days of packaging the Configuration Manager Client were over.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/configmgr-client-hybrid-autopilot/feature-cfg-ap.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proactively Renaming Hybrid Azure AD Joined Devices</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/hybrid-join-computer-rename-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 20:10:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/hybrid-join-computer-rename-again/</guid>
      <description>Nothing has really changed in the Hybrid Join Autopilot space when it comes to device names, and we&amp;rsquo;re still stuck with useless naming conventions for these devices; sometimes a prefix and random characters just isn&amp;rsquo;t a good enough identification method for Windows devices.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/hybrid-join-computer-rename-again/feature-computer-rename.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrofitting Windows Autopilot Group Tags</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/windows-autopilot-retrofitting-group-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 15:55:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/windows-autopilot-retrofitting-group-tags/</guid>
      <description>Now I don&amp;rsquo;t think I promised that I&amp;rsquo;d cover off bulk tagging Autopilot devices in a previous post, but you know, I was running low on things to write about. So here we are.
As I like to practice what I preach, I&amp;rsquo;d left myself the task of updating 1000&amp;rsquo;s of Autopilot devices with a new Group Tag after a successful Proof-of-Concept implementation of a suitable convention and syntax.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/windows-autopilot-retrofitting-group-tags/feature-autopilot-bulk-tag.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Available User Languages on Windows Devices</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/windows-autopilot-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 14:22:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/windows-autopilot-languages/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered how to ensure that a number of languages are available for selection to end users on shared Windows 10 devices? The thought hadn&amp;rsquo;t crossed my mind, but then again, you encounter new use cases and requirements on a weekly basis.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/windows-autopilot-languages/feature-autopilot-lang.jpg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Power of Windows Autopilot Group Tags</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/autopilot-power-of-group-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 10:03:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/autopilot-power-of-group-tags/</guid>
      <description>So you&amp;rsquo;re using Windows Autopilot in some shape or form to deploy Windows 10/11 devices to your users, and you&amp;rsquo;re probably already familiar with the Autopilot dynamic group queries used for targetting these devices, right? Good.
So what if you have multiple deployment profiles, or different device use cases with the same profile, or different user personas, or test and pilot deployments, or a range of applications, configurations or scripts that you want to separate out to the devices or users of the devices?</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/autopilot-power-of-group-tags/feature-autopilot-tags.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renaming Windows Autopilot Hybrid Joined Devices</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/hybrid-join-computer-rename/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 21:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/hybrid-join-computer-rename/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;ve probably hit the limitation with Windows Autopilot Hybrid Azure AD Join deployments and the device name templates being less than flexible, restricting to only a prefix and, well, that&amp;rsquo;s it.
You&amp;rsquo;ve also probably been asked whether you can configure the device name to match an asset tag or another unique bit of information, well this script, adapted from an existing one by Michael Niehaus can help.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/hybrid-join-computer-rename/feature-computer-name.png" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
