<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Settings Catalog on MEM v ENNBEE - Battles with Modern Device Management</title>
    <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/tags/settingscatalog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Settings Catalog on MEM v ENNBEE - Battles with Modern Device Management</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© 2024 Nick Benton, MEM v ENNBEE</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 21:12:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memv.ennbee.uk/tags/settingscatalog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Creating Reusable Groups of Firewall Settings for Microsoft Online Services</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/resusable-firewall-settings-microsoft-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 21:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/resusable-firewall-settings-microsoft-online/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve been living under a rock, or you don&amp;rsquo;t have to deal with firewall and proxy requirements for accessing Microsoft Online services, you probably won&amp;rsquo;t be aware that Microsoft publish their URLs and IP addresses for their services using a web service.
Sadly I don&amp;rsquo;t live under a rock, and when I get the pleasure working with customers who are blocking all inbound and outbound traffic from Windows devices unless there is a matching firewall rule, getting these devices to talk to Microsoft Intune and other Microsoft services, can be a bit of a pain without the web service as a reference.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/resusable-firewall-settings-microsoft-online/feature-fwrug.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modernising Microsoft Intune Firewall Rule Policies</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/settings-catalog-firewall-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 21:40:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/settings-catalog-firewall-rules/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever experienced the joys of migrating Group Policy and in particular Windows Defender Firewall rules away from Group Policy to Microsoft Intune, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably encountered the Rule Migration Tool, and for now this tool has worked well, beavering away grabbing firewall rules from a source Windows 10 or later device and punting them straight in Microsoft Intune.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/settings-catalog-firewall-rules/feature-firewall.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Assignments in Microsoft Intune: Settings Catalog Profiles</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/managing-intune-assignment-settingscatalog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 19:17:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/managing-intune-assignment-settingscatalog/</guid>
      <description>Fresh off the back of a trawl of a Modern Endpoint Management LinkedIn group, someone wanted the ability to assign existing Settings Catalog profiles in Microsoft Intune to additional Groups&amp;hellip;this sounded like a quick win if you fancy manually doing it, but no one wants that, and as I had experience of dealing with the logic when assigning apps, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give it a go.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/managing-intune-assignment-settingscatalog/feature-assignsc.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Endpoint Privilege Management Policies with PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/automate-endpoint-privilege-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 18:58:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/automate-endpoint-privilege-management/</guid>
      <description>So you&amp;rsquo;re interested in Endpoint Privilege Management in Microsoft Intune, you&amp;rsquo;ve found, begged for, borrowed or stolen the money for shiny new Intune Suite or EPM licenses, and in you&amp;rsquo;re excitement you&amp;rsquo;ve gone and deployed a new policy to audit using the Reporting Scope options, all elevations across your managed Windows 10 and later devices.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/automate-endpoint-privilege-management/feature-epm.png" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
