<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Updates on MEM v ENNBEE - Battles with Modern Device Management</title>
    <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/tags/updates/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Updates on MEM v ENNBEE - Battles with Modern Device Management</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© 2024 Nick Benton, MEM v ENNBEE</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 10:18:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memv.ennbee.uk/tags/updates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Risk Based Windows 11 Feature Update Deployment - Feature Updates</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/windows-11-risk-based-deployment-part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 10:18:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/windows-11-risk-based-deployment-part3/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re almost there now; we&amp;rsquo;ve generated and captured the data from a Feature Update Readiness Report and we&amp;rsquo;ve tagged and grouped devices based on their readiness state using Dynamic Security Groups. All of this is useful when deploying a Windows 11 Feature Update, in this instance 23H2, to devices, so let&amp;rsquo;s look at how we actually deploy the new Feature Update to these groups of devices and get you on your Windows 11 journey.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/windows-11-risk-based-deployment-part3/feature-riskupdate.jpg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk Based Windows 11 Feature Update Deployment - Device Attributes</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/windows-11-risk-based-deployment-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 23:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/windows-11-risk-based-deployment-part2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d strongly suggest, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t already, skimming over the first part of this series as this will give you a good understanding of where we started, and hopefully where we&amp;rsquo;re trying to get to with putting the Feature Update Readiness Reports in Microsoft Intune to good use allowing for a risk based deployment approach of Windows 11 23H2.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/windows-11-risk-based-deployment-part2/feature-riskupdate.jpg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Update Deployment Rings for Managed macOS Devices</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/macos-updates-phased-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 20:05:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/macos-updates-phased-deployment/</guid>
      <description>So you&amp;rsquo;ve pulled the trigger on managing macOS devices in Microsoft Intune, and with this year being the year of macOS for Microsoft (this seems like an oxymoron), you should probably look at how to handle software updates.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting a little while to put this post together, as unlike the monthly release of Windows Updates, macOS updates come few and far between, with the recent release of Sonoma 14.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/macos-updates-phased-deployment/feature-macup.jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk Based Windows 11 Feature Update Deployment - Reporting</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/windows-11-risk-based-deployment-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 23:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/windows-11-risk-based-deployment-part1/</guid>
      <description>At the time of writing we are only a few hundred days away from the end of support of Windows 10 22H2, and really we should all be recommending the move to Windows 11, not just because it&amp;rsquo;s shiny and new, but also it&amp;rsquo;s going to actually get security updates.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/windows-11-risk-based-deployment-part1/feature-riskupdate.jpg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Flexible Approach to Microsoft Update Deployments</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/flexible-update-deployments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 20:07:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/flexible-update-deployments/</guid>
      <description>So this isn&amp;rsquo;t the first time we&amp;rsquo;ve looked at improving the management of updates using Microsoft Intune, and probably won&amp;rsquo;t be the last time either, especially with declarative device management looming, for Apple and hopefully Windows devices, covering configuration of software updates.
But with the introduction of the Windows Autopatch service, and getting hands on with it recently, it prompted me to revisit my previous approach to phased update delivery, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share my findings, this time across not just Windows Updates.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/flexible-update-deployments/feature-updates.jpg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Windows Store Apps Updated with Microsoft Intune</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/updating-windows-store-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 21:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/updating-windows-store-apps/</guid>
      <description>So we&amp;rsquo;re all onboard with the New Microsoft Store, and deploying both UWP and Win32 apps from Microsoft Intune is an absolute breeze, and reduces the effort of deploying applications to a click click next OK exercise. What about the UWP apps that are already installed on a Windows Autopilot device, shouldn&amp;rsquo;t we give them a bit of love?</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/updating-windows-store-apps/feature-storeapps.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically Resizing the WinRE Partition for Windows Update KB5034441</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/winre-parition-resize-kb5034441/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 20:54:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/winre-parition-resize-kb5034441/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve been under a rock, or like me, don&amp;rsquo;t have to manage updates on a Windows device estate any more, chances are you might not have seen the issues with the size of the Windows Recovery Environment or WinRE, partition when applying Windows Updates like KB5034441, luckily Microsoft released a &amp;lsquo;fix&amp;rsquo; for this in KB5028997 to resize the partition to allow for updates to install.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/winre-parition-resize-kb5034441/feature-WinRE.jpg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent Phased Windows Update for Business Deployments</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/windows-update-phased-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 20:07:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/windows-update-phased-deployment/</guid>
      <description>You might have been asked the question, especially from organisations that currently utilise Microsoft Configuration Manager, about how you mimic existing Device Collections used for Software Update deployments in Microsoft Intune.
With Configuration Manager having the backing of Microsoft SQL, and a hardware inventory that collects every granular detail about Windows devices, splitting out your device estate into logical phases is very easy to achieve.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/windows-update-phased-deployment/feature-wu.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating Apple Operating System Compliance Policies</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/apple-os-updating-compliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 20:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/apple-os-updating-compliance/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go over old ground in too much detail, as I&amp;rsquo;ve already covered the importance of keeping your Operating System Compliance Policies up to date in line with the release of new updates, as well as a way to update your compliance policies using Graph and PowerShell.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/apple-os-updating-compliance/feature-appleos.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating Defender Antivirus Compliance Settings</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/defender-antivirus-compliance-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 22:04:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/defender-antivirus-compliance-updates/</guid>
      <description>So one of those rainy days is here, finally, and as I mentioned in a previous post many months ago, I said I&amp;rsquo;d look at ways to update other update based compliance policies periodically.
That time is now, and although we&amp;rsquo;re not focussing on other Operating Systems, we&amp;rsquo;re going to have a look at updating a Microsoft Defender compliance policy with the latest platform update version.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/defender-antivirus-compliance-updates/feature-defender-compliance.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Operating System Compliance Updates</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/operating-system-compliance-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 11:20:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/operating-system-compliance-updates/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about Windows 10 and above Operating System Compliance in Microsoft Intune, and specifically how using &amp;lsquo;Minimum OS Version&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Maximum OS Version&amp;rsquo; is dumb and you should definitely check yourself if you&amp;rsquo;re using this in your environment.
Compliance # If you&amp;rsquo;re already using Microsoft Intune compliance policies, good for you, and extra points if you&amp;rsquo;ve integrated these with Conditional Access policies.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/operating-system-compliance-updates/feature-os-compliance.png" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
