<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>macOS on MEM v ENNBEE - Battles with Modern Device Management</title>
    <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/tags/macos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in macOS on MEM v ENNBEE - Battles with Modern Device Management</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© 2024 Nick Benton, MEM v ENNBEE</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 20:05:09 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://memv.ennbee.uk/tags/macos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Software Update Deployment Rings for Managed macOS Devices</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/macos-updates-phased-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 20:05:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/macos-updates-phased-deployment/</guid>
      <description>So you&amp;rsquo;ve pulled the trigger on managing macOS devices in Microsoft Intune, and with this year being the year of macOS for Microsoft (this seems like an oxymoron), you should probably look at how to handle software updates.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting a little while to put this post together, as unlike the monthly release of Windows Updates, macOS updates come few and far between, with the recent release of Sonoma 14.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/macos-updates-phased-deployment/feature-macup.jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Backgrounds for macOS New and Classic Microsoft Teams Apps</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/macos-teams-new-backgrounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 21:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/macos-teams-new-backgrounds/</guid>
      <description>This isn&amp;rsquo;t the first time we&amp;rsquo;ve looked at deploying backgrounds for Microsoft Teams on macOS, but it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since we answered an internet strangers question, and hopefully my scripting has come on a little way since then (spoiler: it hasn&amp;rsquo;t).
Now that the &amp;lsquo;New&amp;rsquo; Microsoft Teams app is the de facto version available to download from Microsoft replacing the &amp;lsquo;Classic&amp;rsquo; one, we should at least look at how it handles uploaded backgrounds and if required update our existing script to support not only the &amp;lsquo;Classic&amp;rsquo; version, but the &amp;lsquo;New&amp;rsquo; version too.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/macos-teams-new-backgrounds/feature-newteams.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting macOS National Cyber Security Centre Security Settings</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/macos-ncsc-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 13:22:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/macos-ncsc-revisited/</guid>
      <description>We looked at some of the ways to secure macOS devices in Microsoft Intune, aligned with the NCSC platform guidance in macOS National Cyber Security Centre Security Settings in Intune, but this was when macOS device management in Intune was, at best, in beta.
General hardening has been covered previously by Hubert Maslowski in their post that covers device compliance and configuration settings, but we&amp;rsquo;re looking at ensuring that the macOS devices meet the National Cyber Security Centre settings, including Cyber Essentials requirements.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/macos-ncsc-revisited/feature-macosncsc.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Teams Backgrounds to macOS Devices</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/macos-teams-backgrounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 20:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/macos-teams-backgrounds/</guid>
      <description>What happens when a stranger on the Internet asks you to look at something they&amp;rsquo;ve got a problem with? Well clearly you jump at the chance and hope that it&amp;rsquo;s not a body part this time. So here we are, looking at how to deploy Microsoft Teams Backgrounds to macOS devices using Intune, for organisations without the licensing to allow for corporate branding using Microsoft Teams Premium Experience.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/macos-teams-backgrounds/feature-teamsmac.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating Apple Operating System Compliance Policies</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/apple-os-updating-compliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 20:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/apple-os-updating-compliance/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go over old ground in too much detail, as I&amp;rsquo;ve already covered the importance of keeping your Operating System Compliance Policies up to date in line with the release of new updates, as well as a way to update your compliance policies using Graph and PowerShell.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/apple-os-updating-compliance/feature-appleos.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Device Migration and Automated Device Enrolment Profile Assignment</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/apple-ade-profile-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 19:57:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/apple-ade-profile-assignment/</guid>
      <description>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve made the financial sensible decision to migrate to Microsoft Intune for your Apple device management needs, you&amp;rsquo;ve got your Apple Push Certificate, sorted your Enrolment Token, added Intune as an MDM provider, and now you&amp;rsquo;ve got all your iOS/iPadOS devices happily sitting synchronised in Intune waiting to be deployed using Apple&amp;rsquo;s Automated Device Enrolment.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/apple-ade-profile-assignment/feature-apple-ade.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating and Assigning App Categories the Smart Way</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/creating-assigning-app-categories/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 19:57:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/creating-assigning-app-categories/</guid>
      <description>Everyone likes managing clients apps in Microsoft Intune, the grind of packing Windows apps, the chore of selecting Managed Google Play apps, the joy of assigning Apple VPP app licenses in Apple Business Manager&amp;hellip;all good fun.
What about assigning App Categories, do you want to be manually updating hundreds of Apps with categories?</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/creating-assigning-app-categories/feature-appcategories.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>macOS National Cyber Security Centre Security Settings in Intune</title>
      <link>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/ncsc-macos-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 11:55:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/ncsc-macos-settings/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever had to implement baseline security settings, whether this be Centre for Internet Security (CIS), Cyber Security Essentials (CSE), or National Cyber Security Centre (NCSC), you&amp;rsquo;ll probably have encountered some level of pain when it comes to non-Microsoft devices, as the guidance, is, well, complicated.
NCSC do provide documented guides for macOS along with a GitHub repo containing a script and a list of recommended security settings, but what do these look like in Microsoft Intune?</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://memv.ennbee.uk/posts/ncsc-macos-settings/feature-macosncsc.jpg" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
